# Prateek Parab

+1 (312)-478-5117 | pparab@hawk.iit.edu | Rockledge, FL | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

Focused and quick-learning Software Engineer with 1+ years of experience in computer science, programming and proficiency in a wide array of languages like Python, C#, Golang, Java and frameworks like Flask, Django, Express etc. along with superior multi-tasking abilities, high adaptability and pro team player qualities.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer, EAGL Technology - Albuquerque, NM

Jul 2019 – Present

- Built a real-time weapon detection system using Trueface api and cloud ML services, Python.
- Built an NFC mobile app using Xamarin(C#) with mfa capability and backend in Asp.net.
- Implemented an efficient triangulation algorithm in Python and integrated with Google maps api.
- Built a desktop notifier using C#, RabbitMQ to send data to the client machine.
- Implemented JWT authentication using C# and created a WebRTC alternative using Opency-python and Flask.
- Deployed the Authentication server and media server on cloud and connected to a remote PostgreSQL db.
- Migrated company's proprietary IOT code from C to Golang.
- Dockerized the python code implementation.
- Created a Key mgmt. portal in Flask and deployed it on Google cloud platform(GCP) and digital ocean.

### Software Developer, Ubees Inc. - New York, NY

Jul 2018 - Jan 2019

- Developed a cross platform app in react native with app size (< 40 MB)</li>
- Built an efficient tracking algorithm in android.
- Implemented web services using REST API.
- Captured and stored Real time sensor data in MongoDB with backend in node.js.
- Successfully migrated data from MongoDB to PostgreSQL.

#### Software Development Intern, Larsen & Toubro – Mumbai, India

Dec 2016 - Jan 2017

- Implemented progressive web app using. Node.js, html, JavaScript.
- Developed an interactive chatbot using Microsoft QnA maker api.
- Developed a chatbot using Dialogflow and deployed on Facebook.

#### **SKILLS**

Technologies: Python, Java, C, JavaScript, React, Node, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Git, Mongo, Bash, Node, MySQL,

AWS, Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, Docker, Golang, Jira, GCP.

**Operating systems:** Windows, Linux, Raspbian.

**Tools:** Eclipse, Spyder, Postman, Jupyter notebook, VS code, Android studio, MS Project, Xcode.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL

Aug 2017 - May 2019

Master of Computer Science

Coursework: Algorithm's, Big data, ML, Project mgmt, App devt., Web apps., Computer vision

Mumbai University, Mumbai, India Jul 2013 - Aug 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Coursework: Theory of Computation, Data Structures, Operating systems, Computer networks

## **PROJECTS**

# Stock market web application project:

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

- Implemented a stock market web application from scratch using Java, Apache tomcat web server.
- Functionalities of the project include, buying and selling real time stocks, parsing data from live json, auto fill features, graphical analysis for stocks bought.
- Project data operations implemented on MySQL database.

### Implementation of facial recognition with transfer learning

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed a neural net from scratch using Python, Tensorflow and Keras.
- Performed data transformation and loading on the dataset from Kaggle.
- Trained the neural net for those datasets and calculated precision, recall, accuracy.
- Implemented transfer learning and achieved higher accuracy by accurately tuning hyperparameters.

Chat application: April 2019

- Developed a chat application using Node.js and socket.io.
- Front-end developed using Express framework.
- Real time notification of the message along with the username
- Added the functionality for multiple socket creation for multiple users.

## Deep learning object classification using Back propagation

Feb 2019

- Implemented pre-processing operations such as reshaping, flattening and created an image vector.
- Built 2 models i) A 2-layer neural net ii) L-layer deep neural network.
- Implemented forward and back propagation from scratch in Python and generate trained parameters.
- Used trained parameters to predict labels and achieved 90% accuracy.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Neural networks and Deep learning, Natural language processing, Machine learning (recommender systems)
- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization.
- Full stack web development, Blockchain essentials, Tableau